welcome back everyone
and today we are going to go through the steam age
now, the first objective we have here is probably to get better tools
those tools make the game way easier
so we will try to get those as quickly as possible
but to do that
we need a few things
now, I think you can skip some of this stuff
you can get the steel in some dungeons
I'm going to show it
but I think the real issue is getting the blocks of iron
because to make a tool forge
which is what is required to make those tools
you need some blocks
but to make blocks
I think you need a compressor
you can't make blocks in any other way
so let's slowly try to go through all of the quests
to power those machines
we are going to need some steam
and we already made in the last episode two Small Coal Boilers
those will burn coal to make steam
and we can put water inside those using buckets
probably that water will be enough
it shouldn't really use much water
this is a really weak boiler
so theoretically I could just run it like that
but ideally you want an automated water fed system instead of manually inserting water
so, I didn't even decide what I want to do, to be honest
but in the multiblock goals
there is a nice quest to get you some water
now, this is the first way to get passive water
this is nice because you build it
and then it passively keeps producing water
and I was thinking about skipping it
but you know what
let's get this one
so, to make this one
we need sticky resin
I was wondering, OK
we do need sticky resin
usually, you can use slime balls
but for this specific one
you do need sticky resin
so, to get sticky resin
the first thing you have to do is to find a IC2 rubber tree
which is this tree that looks like that
this tree should have some gems around it
it's like an orange, OK
when you see this thing
you can click with a treetap to obtain the sticky resin
after a while it's pops back
so you can leave these trees there
wait like a few minutes
and it should be able to be extracted again
or you can try and force more out, but
after you do it too many times
you basically break the point
and it will never make it again
so if you are intended on removing the tree
just do what I just did
otherwise if you want to do a farmer
just leave the log there
and only collect it when it can be collected
you can also get a little bit of resin while breaking the logs if you are lucky
sometimes it does
but the drop rate is a little bit low
and after collecting enough resin
we can finally craft our new water source
this tank is not from GregTech but it's from railcraft
that means you cannot wall share this one
also, we need some pipes
those should be more than good enough for just water
wooden pipes cannot handle gases
and there is a limit at the temperature at which each pipe can carry fluids
so to move steam, we will need bronze pipes
but for water just go with wooden
I think I'm going to place this tank right here
it produces a different amount of water
depending on the humidity of the biome
this biome has an 80% humidity
so it basically works at 80% speed
I think generally 60% and above is probably good enough
I should also get a 2x buff if it has view of the sky
if you build it underground
it produces half the amount of water
and here you can see the water production
this isn't much
but it's should be more than enough for
two Small Coal Boilers that we have
OK, steam is pushed out from the sides of those
while water can be input from the bottom, OK
to connect pipes you need a wrench
and you just click
OK, that's annoying
you connect everything
there's a thing
this fluid behaves like a fluid
I mean not really
if fluid moves inside the pipes
it can go up and down whatever
but things that if there is some fluid inside the pipe
it keeps trying to go in every direction
so if you want the fluid to go from one point to the other
it's better to Shift + Click with your wrench to force the flow direction
this helps for multiple reasons
I heavily suggest doing that on every pipe that
where the fluid is supposed to move in a forced direction
you can set a key binding to toggle line mode
which will allow you to just do a whole line with one click
finish this, OK
as you can see the water is flowing to the boilers
water level is slowly rising
this one is fed first
once this one is filled up
this one will get more water
you don't really need that much water with those
here we have our steam pipe
we're going to do something
and here we will have our machines
as far as I remember, you
I don't think you can automate those
maybe you can
but I don't think
I'm going to feed those charcoal
and once the boiler reaches one hundred degrees
it will start outputting steam
and of course, we need some machine
the first machine is going to be an Alloy Smelter
now, this machine is quite thirsty of steam
you can see here how much steam it has
this is a relatively new
back in the day you had to guess how much steam it had inside
so my suggestion here is try to make sure this one is always on the green before starting this machine
because otherwise it will not be able to work
the first use you are going to use this for is making bronze with a better yield
it makes four ingots out of three copper plus one tin
when we do that manually by shredding the ingots and mixing dust
we end up losing one dust every four
now, as you can see
that is draining more steam than those are producing
and if the needle reaches zero
it's going to get stopped and keep clunking
also, another thing is that after its finishes process
it has to vent out the exhaust steam
so you click with the wrench to set a side where it will vent out steam
if you run out of steam
it's going to completely stop the process, reset
and it will keep doing a little bit of process
then run out of steam, fail, restart
and it will keep sucking in steam without ever doing anything
if you ever get this one stuck
the only thing you probably want to do is to just disconnect the pipe
then you let you let a lot of steam buffer up inside the pipes
and once you have some steam buffering inside the actual generators
you can connect back the pipe
make sure you have enough steam to actually craft it
you can do some calculation
theoretically
multiply by two the total amount of energy units
so six thousand
and that should be the amount of steam required
so, that recipe we are doing should take three thousand energy units
if this steam it's six thousand milli-buckets of steam
we have eight thousand in each pipe
so it's probably enough
connected, now it should get a lot of steam, hopefully
and it should be able to finish
and maybe remove the ingredients so it doesn't get stuck again
at this tier, probably you want a better steam generator
but we're going to see those later
right now just playing like that
like I want to show you everything that can happen
so, you know more or less what you did wrong and how to deal with it
by the way, the way I can see fluids inside the pipes
inside tank and inside chests
like to see the items inside inventories without opening inventories
you need to keep in your baubles the Holo Glasses
you get those as a reward from this quest which was back in the stone age
in the stone age, when you make the coal boiler
you're given as a reward those glasses
you keep those there
and you can see inventories
like without those
I cannot see what's inside chests
and I cannot see what's inside the pipes
if you keep those
you can see what's inside
then, after quickly crafting the most complex piston recipe ever
we also got our compressor
this compressor will allow us to get the blocks needed
and we also unlocked the steel quest
now, to get steel, we actually need a Brick Blast Furnace
which however is a really really tough task to do
so I heavily suggest not to work on this one right now
but rather look for steel somewhere else
look for steel in the dungeons
to get the tool forge
you only need the probably a few ingots
but to follow the quest
just try to loot 8 steel ingots from a dungeon
but before diving into some dungeon
we probably want some better weapons
so, first of all, we're going to make a smeltery
I think this is famous enough
and not going to explain you how it works
the thing that is slightly different in GTNH is that
when you take some hot stuff like lava bucket in your hands
you will start taking damage
and if you want to bring that back to your base you will need some cake gloves
I think those used to be called pizza gloves not cake
well, we have cake now
say cake gloves
you had to put those into the correct slots
you'll get an achievement
OK, and you stop taking damage
so you can walk normally or you enable teleportation
and you have to hold the hot item in your hands
if you don't
you lose the buff and you start taking damage again
the same thing applies to tanks that contain it
with that we can start melting stuff we looted
compressed stone
bunch of other things
and with that we can make a few weapons
and we can also make
if you had some luck and found some obsidian parts
or if you found some steel ingots already
you can make either out of obsidian or steel a pickaxe
those can dig obsidian which will be required later for the obzenite
and remember that you can upgrade your tools
maybe in this case you want a second pickaxe
but I'm going to get the hammer soon
so it should be fine to make a obsidian pickaxe
and after getting a few weapons, we are ready to dive into a dungeon
there are many dungeons you can find
the brick house I talked so much in the past episode is one of those
but there are other dungeons
they look all different on the surface with different buildings
but more or less on the bottom layers they look the same
all of those have some kind of stair that has to go down
and there are like four layers of dungeon
each layer has better rewards but tougher enemies
OK, this one I actually did try to get there already
but I failed
so there I am
let's see how does it go
I'm not good at PvE
it may be a little bit cheaty
but you can even use the NEI search function to even locate the loot chests that contain the steel
I'm not a fan of fighting PvE games or dungeon exploration games
so I'm just going to tunnel my way to the little bit of steel we need
and as soon as I can grab it
I'm just going to leave that dungeon and go back to our progression
and I wanted to remind you that you don't even have to get steel this way
you could make steel with a Brick Blast Furnace
but that's a long task
and I think getting just a little bit of steel to get the tools we're going to get soon is worth it to go in a dungeon for that steel
other than steel, we will also need a lot of zinc
which can also be found in dungeons or can be found as gravel ore on the surface
and a little bit of obsidian
as usual, collecting obsidian is incredibly slow
so I highly suggest adding some redstone to your pickaxes
and with that
we can finally make our obzenite plates
meanwhile we also compress some iron into blocks
and with that
we can finally make the better tools
first one is the lumber axe
which can chop down a complete tree in a single click
and the hammer
which is a pickaxe that can collect nine blocks at once
right now it doesn't look much powerful
and that's because I use the first materials I could get access to
so it's just a bunch of iron and a little bit of obsidian
there are better materials
you can try to figure out what parts you want to use to make your tools
but I just want with a cheap one
and after using it a little bit
it will level up, allowing us to add some lapis lazuli
that will allow us to get up to three times the yield
and that will give us so many resources that we will quickly fill up all of our inventory with precious ores
and now it's time to get us some good backpacks
and of course we shall also get some drawers now and the iron chests
and if you found enough steel, you can also get an even better backpack
which can be actually equipped in a special slot
and will allow you to carry with you all of the tools you always want to have with you
finally, the last usage we can have for steel is to get a flint and steel
which of course we can use to go to the nether
and it has a lower chance of working in this pack
this is going to be way harsher than vanilla Minecraft
there are going to be super annoying mobs
but the reason why it may be worth to get there is because digging in nether has a way higher yield
you also don't find the random gravel or dirt to spot that keep annoying
you do find lava though
and now that we are so rich
we can finally get new machines
the first machine we will get is the macerator
always remember the vent out
which can quickly macerate many things that makes getting clay super easy if you can find terracotta
and if you actually use it on ores, it will double the yield
now, using this macerator to double ores is really not worth it in my opinion
so maybe you want to use this for some specific goals
but most likely
this first macerator you only want to use it to get a few things like
macerating terracotta for clay most, yeah
the main usage of this one is just getting clay dusts in my opinion
next machine we're going to use is the forge hammer
this one uses a lot of steam
but it can be worth it
maybe once you get a better steam generator
it can turn crushed ores into dust super quickly
but it uses really a lot of steam to do so
at least you don't ruin a tool to do that
and but the main usage of this one is to make plates more efficiently
once again, it uses so much steam that you may not want to use it right now
you would probably want to wait for a better steam generation
but it gives you 50% more plates than if you did that in a crafting table
next we have the steam extractor
which actually uses almost no steam to work
and this one can extract raw rubber out of slime balls or raw resin
use that raw rubber to produce actual rubber ingots
which you turn into plates so that we can get the piston boots
those boots will allow you to jump 3 blocks tall
which is super handy and will also give you some buff when you sprint
and they also do the auto-stepping when you go around
those make exploring, moving around and everything else way easier
and don't forget that you can buy pistons in the vending machine with the coins you got from the quest
if you don't like all of the crafting that it takes to make those
which nowadays is not even a big deal since we have NEI auto-crafting
but you know, you have those coins, may as well use those
I think that's a good usage for those coins
and with that, we should basically be ready to actually work on higher tier things
but if we use those machines like that to try to go to the next age
it will take us forever
so, this was nice to get the few quality of life I wanted to rush
but we actually have to rebuild all of our steam machines using the bigger multiblocks
if we actually want to do progress in a realistic and enjoyable time
but I think that I'm going to dedicate a whole episode just to the whole steam progression done properly
so all of the multiblocks, some automation and whatever else we can do
so see you next time
bye bye
欢迎回来，各位
今天我们要通关蒸汽时代
我们的第一个目标大概是做出更好的工具
这些工具可以让游戏流程更轻松
所以我们要尽快做出它们
但要做出它们
我们需要一些东西
我想你可以跳过这些东西
你可以在一些地牢里得到钢
我会展示给大家看
但我认为真正的要解决问题是铁块
因为要制作工具装配台
就是制造这些工具所需要的那个工具台
你需要一些块
而要做出块
我想你需要一个压缩机
你无法用其他方式制造方块
所以让我们慢慢尝试完成所有的任务
要给机器供能
我们需要一些蒸汽
上一集我们做了两个小型燃煤锅炉
可以烧煤制造蒸汽
我们可以用水桶把水放进去
也许这么多水就足够了
它应该要不了太多水
这是一个很拉的锅炉
所以理论上这样就可以让它开始产蒸汽了
但理想情况下，你需要一个自动供水系统，而不是手动填充水
说实话我还没决定要做什么呢
但在“多方块目标”这一章里面
有个不错的任务来获得水
这是第一种被动生产水的方法
这个多方块好在，只要你建了它
它就会不断被动地产生水
我在考虑跳过它
您猜怎么着？
我们还是搓一个这个吧
那么，要搓这个多方块
我们需要黏性树脂
我在想，好吧
我们确实需要黏性树脂
一般情况下，你可以使用黏液球代替
但对于这个特定的配方
你确实需要黏性树脂
那么，要得到黏性树脂
你要做的第一件事就是找到一棵 IC2 橡胶树
这棵树看起来像这样
这棵树周围应该有树脂囊
看起来像个橘子的东西
当你看到这个东西
你可以用木龙头右键来获得黏性树脂
过一会儿它又会重新出现
所以你可以把这些树放着不管
等几分钟
它应该可以再次提取
或者你可以试着提取出更多树脂，但是
在你做了太多次之后
这个地方基本就被你榨干了，一滴不剩了
它再也不会出树脂了
所以如果你打算移除这棵树
就做我刚刚做的
否则如果你是偏采集派的话
把原木放着不管就行了
只要在可以收获的时候收获就行
如果够幸运的话，你也可以在砍伐原木的同时得到一些树脂
有时候会掉
掉落率有点低
在收集到足够的树脂后
我们终于可以搓新的水源了
这个集水器不是 GT 的，而是 RC 的
这意味着它不能与其他多方块共用结构方块
还有，我们需要一些管道
这些用来输水够用了
木质管道不能输送气体
而且每个管道输送流体有各自的温度限制
所以要输送蒸汽，我们需要青铜管道
但对于水，只需使用木制的就好
我想我要把这个集水器放在这里
它产水的速率有一定浮动
取决于生物群系的湿度
这个生物群系有80%的湿度
所以它基本上是以满速的80%工作
我觉得一般来说60%以上就足够了
如果集水器是露天的，应该有2倍的增益
如果你把它建在地下
它产生水的速度只有一半
在这里你可以看到水的产量
没有很多
但这应该足够应付
我们的两个小型燃煤锅炉了
好的，蒸汽从锅炉侧面输出
而水可以从底部输入，好的
你需要扳手来连接管道
你只需右键
好吧，真烦人
连接好所有管道
有一件事值得注意
GT 的流体表现得像流体
但不完全是流体
如果流体在管道内流动
它可以向各个方向流动
但是如果管道里有流体
它会一直试图向各个方向流动
所以如果你想让流体从一个点流到另一个点
最好用扳手 Shift 加右键来固定流动方向
这么做的原因有好几个
如果你觉得流体应该向某个方向移动的话
我强烈建议在每个管道上都固定好方向
你可以绑定一个按键来切换扳手的直线模式
让你可以一键完成整行流向控制
搞定，好
你能看到水正在流向锅炉
水位在慢慢上升
这个先装满
一旦这个装满了
这个会得到更多的水
在这个阶段你不需要那么多水
这是我们的蒸汽管道
我们要做点什么
我们要在这里放机器
据我所知，你……
你应该不能自动化这些
也许你可以做到
但我不认为……
我去给那些锅炉加木炭
一旦锅炉达到100度
它会开始产生蒸汽
当然，我们需要一些机器
第一台机器是合金炉
这台机器消耗蒸汽十分恐怖
你可以在这里看到它有多少蒸汽
这是一个相对比较新的特性
放以前，你得猜里面有多少蒸汽
所以我的建议是，尽量确保指针在启动机器之前在绿色区域
因为不这样的话它就无法工作
合金炉的第一个用途是以更高产率制造青铜
它用三个铜加一个锡做四个锭
如果我们通过手动粉碎锭、混合粉
每做四份就会损失一份青铜粉
现在，如你所见
每秒消耗的蒸汽比产生的多
如果指针达到零
它会停下来，持续被卡住，发出声音
另一件要注意的事是，在它完成配方后
它必须排出多余的蒸汽
用扳手右键设置一个排出蒸汽的面
如果你没有蒸汽了
它会完全停止配方，重置
然后有一点进度
然后耗尽蒸汽，失败，重新启动
它会一直吃蒸汽，但什么也不做了
如果出现这种卡住的情况
你应该做的就是断开管道
然后让管道缓存大量蒸汽
一旦你在锅炉里有了一些蒸汽缓存
你可以接回管道
确保你有足够的蒸汽来完成配方
你可以做一些计算
理论上讲
将 EU 总量乘以2
六千
这应该是所需的蒸汽量
配方需要 3000 EU
换算成蒸汽是 6000 mB 蒸汽
每个管道能缓存 8000 mB
所以应该足够了
连接上了，现在应该存了很多蒸汽，希望如此
它应该能够完成配方
也许该把原料去掉，这样它就不会再卡住了
在这个阶段里，也许你想要一个更好的生产蒸汽的机器
但我们稍后会看到这些
现在就这样就行
我是想向你展示可能发生的方方面面
那样你或多或少知道你做错了什么，以及如何处理它
顺便说一下，我可以看到管道里的流体
包括缸里的和箱子里的
想在不打开物品栏的情况下查看里面的物品
你需要把全息眼镜放在你的饰品栏里
全息眼镜是从这个石器时代的任务中获得的奖励
在石器时代章节，当你制造燃煤锅炉时
你就会得到这些眼镜作为奖励
你把眼镜戴上
你就可以看到库存了
如果没有它
我看不到箱子里有什么
我看不到管道里有什么
如果你戴上
你就可以看到里面有什么
然后，在快速制作了有史以来最复杂的活塞配方之后
我们做出了压缩机
这个压缩机将让我们做出所需的块
也解锁了钢的任务
现在，为了得到钢，我们需要一个砖高炉
然而，这是一项非常非常艰巨的任务
所以我强烈建议现在不要做这个
而是去别的地方找钢
在地牢里寻找钢
获得工具装配台
你只需要几个锭
但为了任务
你可以从地牢里搜刮八个钢锭
但在潜入地牢之前
我们可能需要更好的武器
首先，我们要做一个冶炼炉
我想匠魂应该已经足够出名了
所以我不打算向你解释它是如何工作的
GTNH 中略有不同的是
当你手里拿着岩浆桶之类的热东西
你会开始受到伤害
如果你想把它带回你的基地，你需要一副蛋糕手套
我记得以前叫披萨手套，不是蛋糕
现在叫蛋糕了
说到蛋糕手套
你必须把它们放在正确的栏位里
放反了你会获得一个成就
好的，现在就不会受到伤害了
你可以正常行走或者你传送了
以及，你必须把热的东西握在手里
如果你不这样做
你就会失去增益效果，又开始受到伤害
同样的事情也适用于装东西的储罐
有了它，我们可以开始融化我们搜刮来的东西
压缩石头
一堆其他的东西
用它我们可以制造一些武器
我们还可以制作
如果你运气好找到一些黑曜石零件
或者如果你已经找到了一些钢锭
你还可以制作黑曜石或钢镐
这些镐可以挖掘黑曜石，为之后制作锌曜钢做准备
记住，你也可以升级工具
也许在这种情况下你想要第二把镐
但我很快就会拿到锤
所以做黑曜石镐应该没问题
有了一些武器后，我们准备潜入地牢
你可以找到很多地牢
我上一集讲的砖房就是其中之一
但还有其他地牢
它们表面上看起来都不一样，是不同的建筑
但在底层，它们看起来或多或少是一样的
所有地牢都有某种必经的阶梯下去
地牢一共四层
每一层都有更好的奖励，但也有更难对付的敌人
好的，这个我确实已经下过了
但我失败了
所以我又来了
让我们看看进展如何
我不擅长 PvE
这可能有点作弊嫌疑
但你可以使用 NEI 搜索功能来定位包含钢的战利品箱
我不喜欢战斗 PvE 游戏或地下城探索游戏
所以我要挖地道到我们需要的一点点钢
一旦我得到得到足够的钢
我要离开地牢回归科技主线
我想提醒你，你甚至不必这样得到钢
你完全可以用砖高炉炼钢
但那是个漫长的任务
我认为只要得到一点钢来获得我们很快就会得到的工具
就值得去地牢里找那块钢
除了钢，我们还需要大量的锌
它可以在地牢里找到，或者在地表发现沙砾矿石
我们还需要一点黑曜石
像往常一样，收集黑曜石非常慢
所以我强烈建议在你的镐上添加一些红石
有了这个
我们终于可以制作黑曜石板了
同时我们也可以把一些铁压缩成块
有了这个
我们终于可以制造更好的工具
第一个是伐木斧
它可以一键砍倒一棵完整的树
还有锤
这是一把可以同时收集九个方块的镐
现在它看起来不太强大
那是因为我使用了我能弄到的第一批材料
只是一堆铁和一点黑曜石
还有更好的材料
你可以试着弄清楚你想用什么部件来制作你的工具
但我现在只想要一个便宜的
用了一会儿后
工具会升级，我们可以添加一些青金石
这将使我们能够获得三倍的产量
这将为我们提供海量资源，物品栏很快就会被珍贵的矿石填满
是时候做些好的背包了
当然，我们现在还应该做一些抽屉和铁箱子
如果你找到足够的钢，你还可以做一个更好的背包
它实际上可以安装在一个特殊的栏位中
有了背包你就可以随身携带所有你想带的工具
最后，钢的最后一个用法是用来做打火石
我们当然可以用它去下界
但是在这个整合包里点火成功率会更低
下界将比原版我的世界更难
会有非常烦人的怪物
但它值得 去的原因是在下界挖掘有更高的产量
你也不会碰到那些烦人的沙砾或泥土
但是你的确会碰到岩浆
现在我们资源富裕
我们终于可以做些新机器了
我们要做的第一台机器是研磨机
永远记住，设置排气面
它可以快速研磨许多东西
如果你能找到陶瓦，就很容易得到黏土
如果你用来磨矿石，它的产量会翻倍
现在用这个研磨机来翻倍矿物我觉得还是不值得的
所以也许你想用它来达到一些特定的目标
但最有可能的是
这第一个研磨机你只想用它来得到一些东西，比如
研磨陶瓦，是的
在我看来，这个机器主要用途只是得到黏土粉
下一台我们要用的机器是锻造锤
它会使用很多蒸汽
但这应该是值得的
也许等你有了更好的蒸汽生产手段
它可以超级快地把粉碎矿变成粉
但是这样做需要大量的蒸汽
至少你不用消耗用来粉碎矿石的工具
但它的主要用途是更高效地制作板
再说一遍，它用的蒸汽很多，以至于你可能现在不想用它
你可能要等到蒸汽产量更高的时候再使用它
但它比工作台配方多 50% 的板
接下来我们做了蒸汽提取器
它工作所需的蒸汽几乎可以忽略不计
它可以从黏液球或生树脂中提取生橡胶
用生橡胶生产橡胶锭
你把它变成板，这样我们就可以做出活塞靴
那双靴子能让你跳三格高
这非常方便，在你疾跑时也会给你一些增益
当你四处走动时，它也会自动上台阶
这些让探索、四处走动和所有事情变得更加容易
别忘了你可以用任务中得到的硬币在自动售货机里买活塞
如果你不喜欢制作这些所需的合成的话
现在这甚至没什么大不了的，因为我们有 NEI 自动合成
你获得了那些硬币，不妨花在这上面
我认为这是硬币的优质用法
有了这个，我们基本上准备好了干更高阶段的事情
但是如果我们用现在的那些机器去尝试进入下一个阶段
到死都可能搓不出来
所以，搓一些提升生活质量的东西的话更好
如果我们真的想在合理且愉快的时间里取得爬科技线的话
我们就必须用更大的多方块机器来重建我们所有的蒸汽机
我会在另一集好好讲一下正确如何发展蒸汽能
包括所有的多方块，一些自动化和我们能做的其他事情
所以下次见
拜拜
（愚人节版本 steam gate 加入）